Guide to the Peter Gizzi Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Peter Gizzi papers
1960-2009
YCAL MSS 339
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
36.8
(49 boxes) + 2 gigabytes
The collection consists of material created and accumulated by Peter Gizzi in the course of his literary activities as a poet, editor, and teacher, and documents the creation of his published books of poetry, the publication of the literary journal O·blēk, and his personal and professional relationships with other writers, poets, and publishers. Material includes correspondence with various literary figures; drafts, notes, and proofs relating to Gizzi's published and unpublished work; manuscripts of work published in O·blēk (Issues 1-12) and related correspondence and general business files; manuscripts and related material for limited editions published by O·blēk Editions; typescripts of works by other writers submitted to Gizzi for his review; lecture notes and teaching material; and other papers relating to various aspects of Gizzi's personal and professional life.
Gizzi, Peter, 1959-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from James S. Jaffe on the Ezra Pound Archive Fund, 2009.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 40 (audio cassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 48-49 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Email files in Series VI: Access is restricted during the lifetime of Peter Gizzi. Consult the appropriate curator for further information.
Files in Series VI. Electronic Files, "Restricted files" folder: restricted until 2020 January 1. Consult the appropriate curator for further information.
Copies of other electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Peter Gizzi (1959-)
Peter Gizzi was born in 1959 and grew up in Pittsfield, Massachusetts. He holds degrees from New York University, Brown University, and the State University of New York at Buffalo. His books include The Outernationale (Middletown, CT: Wesleyan University Press, 2007), Some Values of Landscape and Weather (Middletown, CT: Wesleyan University Press, 2003), Artificial Heart (Providence, RI: Burning Deck, 1998), and Periplum, or, I the blaze (Penngrove, CA: Avec Books, 1992). He has also published many limited edition chapbooks, folios, and artists' books. His work has been widely anthologized and translated into numerous languages.
As an editor, Gizzi has overseen O·blēk: A Journal of Language Arts and The Exact Change Yearbook. He has taught at Brown University and the University of California, Santa Cruz. He is currently on the faculty of the University of Massachusetts at Amherst.
Biographical note is based on that in Poets.org (accessed on 8 June 2010).
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of material created and accumulated by Peter Gizzi in the course of his literary activities as a poet, editor, and teacher. The papers and electronic files document the creation of Gizzi's works of poetry, the publication of the literary journal O·blēk, and his personal and professional relationships with other writers, poets, and publishers. Material includes correspondence with literary figures; drafts, notes, and proofs relating to Gizzi's published and unpublished works; manuscripts of work published in O·blēk (issues 1-12), with related correspondence and general business files; manuscripts and related material for limited editions published by O·blēk Editions; typescripts of writings by other writers submitted to Gizzi for his review; lecture notes and teaching material; and other papers relating to Gizzi's personal and professional life.
Arrangement
Organized into six series: I. Correspondence, 1988-2007. II. Writings by Peter Gizzi, 1980-2007. III. O·blēk Files, 1979-2005. IV. Writings by Others, 1990-2007. V. Other Papers, 1960-2006. VI. Electronic Files, 1990s-2009.
O·blēk; American poetry -- 20th Century; American literature -- 20th Century; Literature, Modern -- 20th Century; Poetry, Modern -- 20th Century; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Born digital -- United States -- 20th Century; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Gizzi, Peter, 1959-
- Correspondence, 1988-2007; Series I; 12.04; (14 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged into chronological groupings by year or year span. Within individual groupings, correspondence is often arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. consists of incoming professional and personal correspondence, including letters, cards, and email printouts, with writers, authors, publishers, family and friends.
  - 1988-1995, 10 (Box 1)
  - 1988-1995, 5 (Box 2)
  - 1988-1995, 3 (Box 3)
  - 1990-1999, 23 (Box 4)
  - 1990-1999, 4 (Box 5)
  - 1995-1998, 20 (Box 6)
  - 1995-1998, 3 (Box 7)
  - 1996, 12 (Box 7)
  - 1998-1999, 6 (Box 7)
  - 1998-1999, 15 (Box 8)
  - 2000, 1994-2000; 16 (Box 9)
  - 2000, 1994-2001; 12 (Box 10)
  - 2002-2004, 12 (Box 11)
  - 2002-2005, 16 (Box 12)
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Copies of electronic files available through Access Services: Disks 1-2, Tom Gizzi @ The Red Lion Inn (2004)
  - 2004-2005, 7 (Box 13)
  - 2004-2007, 1990, 2004-2007; 8 (Box 13)
    Includes two audio compact discs: "Cue Art Foundation" and "Anti-War Poetry Through The Ages: Performed by Michael Fischetti".
  - 2004-2007, 17 (Box 14)
- Writings by Peter Gizzi, 1980-2007; Series II; 6.08; (7 boxes)
  Organized into two subseries: Major Works and Other Writings.
  Series II. consists of typescript and autograph manuscript drafts, proofs, and other material relating to Gizzi's published books of poetry and other writings.
  - Major Works
    Published works are arranged chronologically by date of publication.
    - Creeley Madrigal (1991)
      - A Counting - Brown University M.F.A. Thesis, circa 1991 (Box 15)
    - Music for Films (1992)
      - Page Proofs (photocopies), 1992 (Box 15)
      - Annotated typescipt, 1992 (Box 15)
      - Music for Films, 1992 (Box 15)
    - Periplum, or, I the Blaze (1992)
      - Early drafts, 1992 (Box 15)
      - Page proofs, 1992 (Box 15)
      - Manuscript drafts / notebooks pre-1992, before 1992; 3 (Box 15)
      - Early unpublished pre-Periplum manuscript, before 1992 (Box 15)
      - Avec Magazine - Periplum, 1992 (Box 15)
    - Hours of the Book (1994)
      - Page proofs, circa 1994 (Box 15)
      - Early version of M.A. Thesis, 1990s; 3 (Box 15)
    - Ledger Domain (1995)
      - Mollohan - Ledger Domain, 1995 (Box 15)
      - Mechanical Proofs, 1995 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Artificial Heart (1998)
      - Drafts and notebooks, circa 1998; 7 (Box 15)
      - A Textbook of Chivalry, undated; 3 (Box 15)
    - Some Values of Landscape and Weather (2003)
      - Early drafts, 2003; 2 (Box 15)
      - Early drafts and proofs, 2001-2003; 21 (Box 16)
    - Periplum and Other Poems 1987-1992 (2004)
      - Typescripts and proofs, circa 2004; 3 (Box 16)
        Copies of electronic files available through Access Services: Disks 3-4, "Gizzi_PGfig01.jpg" and "Periplum"
      - Drafts and final manuscript, circa 2004; 5 (Box 17)
    - A Panic That Can Still Come Upon Me (2006)
      - Uncorrected page proof, circa 2006 (Box 17)
    - The Outernationale (2007)
      - Working manuscripts, drafts, proofs and notes, 2000s; 17 (Box 17)
      - Working manuscripts, drafts, proofs and notes, 2000s; 18 (Box 18)
  - Other Writings
    - Early unpublished manuscripts, undated (Box 18)
    - An Open Letter of Poetics to Steve Farmer, 1999 (Box 18)
    - Bound writings and typescripts, undated (Box 18)
      Includes "Two Plays" and "21 Attempts At Elegy."
    - Brown University file folder, containing typescripts and poems, undated (Box 18)
    - Susan Howe class on Dickinson, circa 1991; 2 (Box 18)
    - Robert Creeley obituary, 2005 (Box 18)
    - In The Air?, unpublished manuscript, undated (Box 18)
    - Old Letters, 1989 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence and manuscripts, 1983-1987; 2 (Box 19)
      Includes photographs and slides.
    - Expandable file folder, 1984-1985 (Box 19)
      Includes postcards, old photographs, printouts of various works, correspondence, and "Poetry Flash", a newspaper from November 1985.
    - "Rushlight", score, Rick Appelbaum, undated (Box 19)
      Includes poetry by Gizzi, circa 1980s.
    - Memo book with poetry and writings, undated (Box 19)
    - M. Heller, Greek tragedy drama coursework, 1985 (Box 19)
    - Film Comment, magazine, 1984 February (Box 19)
    - Weatherly, various material, 1986 (Box 19)
    - The New Life, various manuscript material, 1980s; 8 (Box 19)
      Includes Rosemarie Waldrop correspondence and poems; material sent by Singing Horse Press; a mechanical from Bernard Waldrop; "E.H." by Claude Richard; Peter Gizzi's NYU Undergraduate essays and thesis; "Moss Lotus" by Julia Spicher; Elizabeth Brundage poems; "In Memory of Louie Zukofsky" by Walter James Miller; "Oedipus Rex" notes and writings; the "Ajax Soph." manuscript; a black binder with notes; a brown folder with poems; "Michael's play" and various poems and correspondence.
    - Composition notebooks, 1980-1990; 15 (Box 20)
      Also includes two photographs of Peter Gizzi, circa 1970s, and negatives.
- O·blēk Files, 1979-2005; Series III; 11.5; (18 boxes)
  Organized into four subseries: Journal Submissions, Correspondence, General Business Files, and O·blēk Editions.
  Series III. consists of material relating to the publication of O·blēk: a journal of the language arts, which was published between 1987 and 1993 and edited by Peter Gizzi with Connell McGrath. Material includes manuscripts, correspondence, page and cover proofs, contracts, subscription lists, financial records, publicity, and related papers. The series also includes material relating to the publication of O·blēk Editions limited edition chapbooks.
  - Journal Submissions
    Arranged largely by journal issue.
    - O·blēk 1 (Spring 1987)
      - Gizzi, Michael. "No Both", 1992; 2 (Box 21)
      - Ragosta, Ray. "From the Varieties of Religious Experience", undated (Box 21)
    - O·blēk 2 (Fall 1987)
      - Gizzi, Michael. "Continental Harmony", 1987 (Box 21)
    - O·blēk 4 (Fall 1988)
      - Mayer, Bernadette. "The Desires to Please Others in Letters", undated (Box 21)
      - Rodefer, Stephen. Poems, 1990 (Box 21)
    - O·blēk 5 (Spring 1989)
      - Davies, Alan. Poems, 1991 (Box 21)
      - Nelson, Gale. "Tracing", undated (Box 21)
      - Waldrop, Keith. "The Plummet of Vitruvius", undated (Box 21)
    - O·blēk 6 (Fall 1989)
      - Daly, Lewis. "Duns Molestation", 1990 (Box 21)
      - Daly, Lewis. "Nemesis Book", undated (Box 21)
    - O·blēk 7 (Spring 1990)
      - Friedlander, Benjamin. "Covenant", 1991 (Box 21)
        Also includes a typescript of Reginald Shepherd's "Don't Take Your Love From Me."
      - Retallack, Joan. "Afterimages", 1990 (Box 21)
      - Waldrop, Keith. Jean Grosjean's "Elegies", undated (Box 21)
    - O·blēk 8 (Fall 1990)
      - Mayer, Bernadette. Poems, 1990 (Box 21)
      - Nelson, Gale. "Courting Fires", 1991 (Box 21)
      - Nelson, Gale. "Formosa", undated (Box 21)
      - Osman, Jena. "Amblyopia", 1990 (Box 21)
    - O·blēk 9 (Spring 1991)
      - Rehm, Pamela. Poems, undated (Box 21)
      - Yau, John. Poems, undated (Box 21)
    - O·blēk 10 (Fall 1991)
      - Berrigan, Ted. "Kerouac Conference, Naropa 1982" (Box 21)
      - Coolidge, Clark. "Holds to the Light", 1991 (Box 21)
      - Howe, Fanny. "Written in Eire", undated (Box 21)
      - Marcus, Benjamin M. "Secret Weather", 1991 (Box 21)
      - Rehm, Pamela. "The Garment In Which No One Had Slept", 1989 (Box 21)
      - Poems, 1989 (Box 21)
    - O·blēk 11 (Spring 1992)
      - Bellen, Martine. "Wild Women", undated (Box 22)
      - Davies, Alan. Poems, 1992 (Box 22)
      - McGrath, Connell. "The Human Properties", undated (Box 22)
    - O·blēk 12 (Spring and Fall 1993)
      - Accepted manuscript, 1993 (Box 22)
      - Annotated manuscripts from various authors, 1990s; 5 (Box 22)
      - Cadiot, Olivier. "Produit Industriel de Fiction", 1991 (Box 22)
      - Financial Records, IRS, Thompson Share, 1991-1992 (Box 22)
      - Fliers and manuscripts, 1990s (Box 22)
      - Gilbert, Alan. "The Eve of Jubilee", 1996 (Box 22)
      - Hale, Terrel. Poems, 1989 (Box 22)
      - Hoelle, J. Nicole. Poems, 1990 (Box 22)
      - Hoelle, J. Nicole. "In All This Blonde Silence", undated (Box 22)
      - Jarnot, Lisa. "Some Other Kind of Mission", 1994 (Box 22)
      - Letters, 1992; 2 (Box 22)
      - Manuscripts, undated; 2 (Box 23)
      - NEA Grant Proposal, 1991 (Box 23)
      - NEA Grant Proposal, 1992 (Box 23)
      - Nelson, Gale. "Passacaglia", 1990 (Box 23)
        Also includes Michael Friedman's "Poem for John Wieners".
      - New conference material, fliers and schedule, 1993 (Box 23)
      - O-12 proof, undated (Box 23)
      - Poetry readings, 1996 (Box 23)
      - Potts, Randall. "Collision Center", 1994 (Box 23)
      - Rehm, Pamela. "Issue II Spec", undated (Box 23)
      - Rehm, Pamela. "To Give It Up", undated (Box 23)
      - Schorn, Brian William. "Retina Documenta", 1991 (Box 23)
      - Smith, Rod. "In Memory of my Theories", undated (Box 23)
      - Smith, Rod. Poems, undated (Box 23)
      - Spahr, Juliana. Emails with Peter Gizzi, 1995 (Box 23)
      - Submission letters and poems, 1990-1992; 3 (Box 23)
      - Waldrop, Rosmarie. "Lavish Absence", undated (Box 23)
    - Various Submissions
      - Jones, Kent. "A Heart in Flower," screenplay, undated (Box 23)
      - Krukowski, Dawn(?). "The Sixties", undated (Box 23)
        Also includes Bernadette Mayer's "The Ethics of Sleep"
      - Waldrop, Rosmarie. "The Reproduction of Profiles", 1987 (Box 23)
      - Waldrop, Keith. "Potential Random", undated (Box 23)
        Also includes Rosmarie Waldrop's "A Key Into the Language of America, chapter 1"; Debra Weinstein's "From Rodent Angel"; Gale Nelson's "Little Brass Pump"; and Alison Bundy's "Mote of Dust".
      - Carlyle, Deanna. "Albiach critique", 1990 (Box 23)
        Also includes Avery E.D. Burns' "On An Occasion to Talk Poetry".
      - Kasper, Michael. "Colonial - English", undated (Box 23)
      - Gilson, William. "Junkyard", 1989 (Box 23)
      - Gregoire, William. Poems (Box 24)
      - Mayer, Bernadette. Writings, 1992 (Box 24)
      - Burdette, Nicole. "Chelsea Hotel Room #225", undated (Box 24)
      - Biebighauser, Kristen. "Left Hand Write", 1992 (Box 24)
      - Hale, Terrel D. "Walking Behind the Window Glass", 1990 (Box 24)
      - Mayer, Bernadette. "A Bernadette Mayer Reader", 1992 (Box 24)
      - Perrìere, Donna Michelle de la. "Shipwreck", 1991 (Box 24)
        Also includes poems by William Gregoire.
      - Bonnett, Ed. Poems, 1990 (Box 24)
      - Raworth, Tom. "Out of the Picture", undated (Box 24)
      - Howe, Fanny. Poems, 1990 (Box 24)
        Also includes poems by Ed Barnett and Elaine Equi.
      - Mayer, Bernadette. "The Formal Field of Kissing", 1989 (Box 24)
      - Springgate, Benjamin. Translation of Paul Celan's "From Threshhold to Threshhold", 1994 (Box 24)
      - Waldrop, Keith. Translation of "Prose Poems by Pierre Revery", undated (Box 24)
      - Waldrop, Keith. "The House Seen From Nowhere", undated (Box 24)
      - Sharma, Prageeta. "The Opening Question", undated (Box 24)
      - Anonymous. "En Amont du Ciel Profane", undated (Box 24)
      - Waldrop, Keith. "The Locality Principle", undated (Box 24)
      - Kunin, Aaron B. "Knowledge Blobs," translation, undated (Box 24)
      - Rothschild, Douglas. "Is", undated (Box 24)
      - Phillips, Patrick. "Ruin", 1995 (Box 24)
      - Burdette, Nicole. "Can I Walk You Home", undated (Box 24)
      - Hess, David. "Everything to Anything", 1994 (Box 24)
      - Yau, John. "In the Realm of Appearances: The Art of Andy Warhol", undated (Box 24)
      - Katsarus, George. "The Traces of a Figure in Dante's Paradiso", undated (Box 24)
      - Morse, Matt. "Creation's Drive", 1994 (Box 24)
      - Ashbery. Xeroxed draft, undated (Box 24)
      - Brown, Margaret. "Footage", 1994 (Box 24)
        Also includes Tandy Sturgeon's "The Billboards South of Blackfoot".
      - Daly, Lew. "Kingdom Studies", undated (Box 25)
        Also includes various poems and a William de Kooning Paintings brochure.
      - Lowenthal, Jessica. Correspondence, 1994 (Box 25)
      - Waldrop, Keith - "The Silhouette of the Bridge", undated (Box 25)
      - Truitt, Sam. "Anamorphosis - Ellen Hower", undated (Box 25)
      - Ellis, Thomas Sayers. "The Maverick Room", undated (Box 25)
      - Ngai, Sianne. "Some Brief Histories of Time", 1993 (Box 25)
      - Lease, Joseph. "The Sun Threshes", 1993 (Box 25)
      - Gregoire, A. William. "Writing For One", undated (Box 25)
      - Sharma, Prageeta. "Life In Both Places", undated (Box 25)
      - Pineda, Cecile. "Redoubt", 1997 (Box 25)
      - Coolidge, Clark. "To The Cold Heart", 1997 (Box 25)
      - Anonymous. "Hayagriva", undated (Box 25)
      - Hofer, Jen. "Mapless", 1994 (Box 25)
      - Pollentier, Nicole. "Fishouts and Flowers", 1993 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence
    - O·blēk 1, 1987 (Box 25)
    - O·blēk 1, 1987 (Box 25)
    - O·blēk 2, 1987 (Box 25)
    - O·blēk 2, 1987 (Box 25)
    - O·blēk 2, 1991 (Box 25)
    - O·blēk 3, 1987-1988 (Box 25)
    - O·blēk 4, 1988 (Box 25)
    - O·blēk 5, 1988-1989 (Box 26)
    - O·blēk 6, 1990 (Box 26)
    - O·blēk 7, 1990 (Box 26)
    - O·blēk 8, 1988-1990 (Box 26)
    - O·blēk 8, 7, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 26)
    - O·blēk 9, 1990 (Box 26)
    - O·blēk 9, 1990-1991 (Box 26)
    - O·blēk 9 Contacts, 1990-1991 (Box 26)
    - O·blēk 10, 1990s (Box 26)
    - O·blēk 10, 1990-1991 (Box 26)
    - O·blēk 11 mechanical, undated (Box 26)
    - O·blēk 12 Contributors correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 26)
  - General Business Files
    - Blank proof paper, undated (Box 26)
    - Blank Supreme Gloss Paper - 8.5 x 11, undated (Box 26)
    - "Current O·blēk" (empty folder), undated (Box 26)
    - "Dine Prints," John Black photographic prints, undated (Box 26)
    - Empty O·blēk envelopes, undated (Box 26)
    - Jabés interview, undated (Box 26)
    - O·blēk Art Print and Cover mechanical, Ben Hipo (?), undated (Box 26)
    - Logo mechanicals, undated (Box 26)
    - Museum Stores, undated (Box 26)
      Copies of electronic files available through Access Services: Disk 5, "Datalist[...]"
    - O·blēk archival photos, undated (Box 26)
    - O·blēk blank invoice forms, undated (Box 26)
    - "O·blēk Office" (empty folder), undated (Box 26)
    - O·blēk postcards, loose papers and pocket notebooks, undated (Box 26)
    - O·blēk stamp, undated (Box 27)
    - Paper - O·blēk and blank, undated (Box 27)
    - Raiche, Dorothy W. Correspondence, 1979 (Box 27)
    - Foundation Certificate of Incorporation and By-laws, 1984-1987 (Box 27)
    - NEA, 1994-1995 (Box 27)
    - Fundraising, 1985-1987 (Box 27)
    - The Magazine, 1987 (Box 27)
    - Financial correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 27)
    - O·blēk cover proofs, volumes 1 - 7, 1987-1990; 2 (Box 27)
    - Small press distribution, 1987-1992 (Box 27)
    - O·blēk archive - Metropolitan Home, 1987-1995 (Box 27)
      Also includes Xui Di's curriculum vitae (circa 1993), Metropolitan Home magazine (November 1987), and R. R. Bowker correspondence (1995).
    - Contracts for O / 8, 1988 (Box 27)
    - IRS Form 1023 - Application for Reorganization of Exemption under 501(c) (3)., 1988 (Box 27)
    - Annual Reports and 88 / 89 Tax return, 1988-1989 (Box 27)
    - Broadsides, 1988-1990 (Box 27)
    - O·blēk printed ephemera, 1988-1990 (Box 27)
    - Press releases and fliers, 1988-1991 (Box 27)
    - Subscriptions O·blēk 12, 1989-1992 (Box 27)
    - Letters to reviewers and editorial and reviews, 1990 (Box 27)
    - O·blēk event cards, 1990s (Box 27)
    - O·blēk cover proofs, volume 10, 1991 (Box 27)
    - Fall 1991 proof and mechanicals, 2 (Box 27)
    - Event flier and Fedex label receipt, 1991 (Box 27)
    - O·blēk proofs and mechanicals, 1991; 3 (Box 27)
    - "Mag. for Peter", 1990-1991 (Box 27)
    - O·blēk publicity business, 1990-1994; 2 (Box 27)
    - O·blēk publicity business, 1990-1994 (Box 28)
      Includes Antoni Tápies slides.
    - Baffling Means Press review sheet / release, 1991 (Box 28)
    - Cover type O / 7, 8, 9, 10 logo mechanicals, etc., 1991 (Box 28)
    - Inland contract, terms and specs, 1991 (Box 28)
    - Santner, Eric L. - "Postwar / Post-Holocaust...", 1991 (Box 28)
    - O·blēk office phone, 1991-1992 (Box 28)
    - Lannan Foundation 1993 grant proposal, NEA copy CLMP Kovlokis Seed Grant, 1991-1993 (Box 28)
    - "Le Cahier du Refuge - 21", booklet, 1992 (Box 28)
    - Check book, 1992-2001 (Box 28)
    - Fundraising letters, 1992-1993 (Box 28)
    - Distribution, 1993-1994 (Box 28)
    - O·blēk taxes, 1993-1994 (Box 28)
    - O·blēk Tax Returns, 1993-1997 (Box 28)
    - O·blēk miscellaneous / taxes, 1994 (Box 28)
      Also includes mechnanicals for "Theory of Tables" by Emmanuel Hocquard.
    - O·blēk bank statements, 1995 (Box 28)
    - Bank statements, 1997-2000; 2 (Box 28)
  - O·blēk Editions
    - Exact Change Yearbook 1995, no 1.
      - Ashbery, John. Pierre Martory translations, undated (Box 31)
      - Beatty, Paul. Correspondence, 1994 (Box 31)
      - "Brit Bids, enter and return to P.G.", undated (Box 31)
      - Canadians, 1994 (Box 31)
      - Champion, Miles. Manuscript, 1994 (Box 31)
      - Chapbooks - yearbook, undated (Box 31)
      - Cole manuscript, 1994 (Box 31)
      - Champion, Miles. "Compositional BonBons Placate", 1994 (Box 31)
      - Coolidge, Clark. "Mary or Marie: Some Versions Of His Versions", 1994 (Box 31)
      - Correspondence and manuscript material, 1994; 2 (Box 31)
      - Crisis and Creativity, 1994 (Box 31)
      - Translated stories of Matilde Daviu, 1994 (Box 31)
      - Dent, Tory. Manuscripts, 1994 (Box 31)
      - Desnos, Robert. "Night of Loveless Nights", undated (Box 31)
        Also includes a letter from Julie Kalendek.
      - "Exact Change Yearbook: 1994-1995," catalog (Box 31)
      - Creede, Gerald and Deanna Ferguson. Manuscripts, 1994 (Box 31)
        Copies of electronic files available through Access Services: Disk 6, "Catriona Strang[...]" (1994)
      - "Gallery - MZ but David Shapiro?", undated (Box 32)
      - Howe, Susan. "Frame Structure", 2000s (Box 32)
      - Howell, Anthony. "First Time in Japan", 1990s (Box 32)
      - Howell, Anthony. "Sonnets, 1974-1994" (Box 32)
      - "In the Night on Winds", undated (Box 32)
      - Kalendek, Julie. "Observatory Occasion", 1989 (Box 32)
        Also includes "The Night of Loveless Nights" by Robert Desnos, translated by Julie Kalendek.
      - Killian, Kevin. Correspondence to Peter Gizzi, 1994 (Box 32)
        Also includes an introduction to "Under the Influence", transcriptions of "Imaginary Elegies" and a revised copy of "Imaginary Elegies".
      - Kim, Mying Mi. Correspondence, 1994 (Box 32)
      - Kopple, K. A. "Marosa di Giorgio writings", translation, undated (Box 32)
        Also includes Michael Palmer correspondence and an overview of "British Section".
      - Lawson, Andrew. Correspondence and manuscripts, 1994 (Box 32)
      - Marcus, Ben. "The Weather Killer", 1994 (Box 32)
        Also includes faxes from Damon Krukowski.
      - McMorris, Mark, 1994 (Box 32)
      - Moriarty, Laura. Correspondence and manuscripts, 1994 (Box 32)
      - Moxley, Jennifer J. "Often Capital", 1994 (Box 32)
      - "Original: Chinese Language-Poetry Group", undated (Box 32)
      - Palmer, Michael. "At Passages", circa 1992 (Box 32)